♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Janine] Mommy, I called Daddy,
so my birthday will be our family bonding.
[Janine] Why is she here?
Janine, you'll be siblings.
I will adopt her.
She needs a mother figure.
[in English] You know, someone
who will be… a good role model for her.
[Audrey] You should get married.
[Leon] If your child is unruly,
don't bring her here just to lose her.
Who was that?
- [Gemma] Oh, that was Sir Leon.
- Ouch.
- Son of a… So stupid.
- [indistinct]
I apologize on her behalf.
If you and Sir Delfin
were single back then,
do you think you could've been together?
[Karla] I wish that were the case, right?
Then Brother Atoy
and I would be your children.
- [Ame] Mm-hmm.
- There's a horseback riding activity here.
I want to ride a horse.
You go ahead. I'll just change. Okay?
[in English] Yes!
[Audrey] Atoy! Atoy!
Don't leave yet. Stay here first.
Um, Janine requested that
we surprise her with a birthday cake.
[in English] Don't forget to make a wish
before you blow your candle, my child.
[Janine] I wish my parents
would get back together,
so our family of three will be complete!
Audrey?
I know how to swim.
I lived on the island for a long time.
Are you alone?
I'm waiting for my father.
He's taking so long.
Kiss each other, please.
- Kiss.
- Hey, she's asking for a kiss.
[staff, in English] One, two, three!
Oh, one more. One more.
[Atoy] One, two. Mmm, mmm, mmm.
PREVIOUSLY
Okay.
[music fades]
- [Janine] Mommy.
- Hmm?
Do you still have feelings for Daddy?
- [light music playing]
- [chuckles]
What are you saying, Ibyang?
Because you and Aunt Audrey
look good together!
When you adopt me,
and you're looking for a mother for me,
Aunt Audrey is a big check for me!
Can't you get back together?
Maybe you still love each other.
That was before, child.
But I think…
Daddy still has a crush on you.
- Oh, Janine!
- [giggles]
[Audrey sighs]
Oh.
- Tatoy is blushing!
- [quirky flourish]
- [Ibyang] Hmm, hmm.
- What blush? That's sunburn!
See, it's so hot.
Oh, you! Hmm, hmm!
It's obvious you still have feelings
for Aunt Audrey!
Just court her.
You're both single anyway.
No.
We're fine like this.
We're friends for Janine's sake.
Mommy, I know you love me so much, but…
I still want a happy family,
with all three of us complete.
Because until now,
I haven't really experienced that.
[in English] I want that
for you too, child.
[in English] But it's not that simple.
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
[snipping]
[sewing machine clacking]
- [gun cocks]
- [gunfire]
[gunfire blasting]
[clicking]
[snipping]
[electronic blipping]
[crickets chirping]
[Ibyang] Ouch!
[soft moan]
- [Ibyang] It hurts.
- You're overreacting.
It doesn't hurt that much.
[Ibyang] Why are you bothering me?
I kept my promise.
I'm letting you bond
with your mommy and daddy.
Here, throw this.
Let's play. Come on.
‪[gentle music playing]
Come on.
[swooshes]
- [chuckles]
- [Janine] You're laughing, huh.
Me too. Catch this.
[swooshes]
[clatters]
- That's the grumpy man.
- [Leon] Hey!
Let's go.
[tense music playing]
You two!
Where are you going?!
She's the one She's the one
who threw it, not me!
Me?
- [Leon] You--
- [Janine] Yes, you!
You lying child!
- Come here!
- Ouch!
I saw you. You threw it!
And now you're blaming your playmate?!
You're a lying child, huh!
[cracks]
[music intensifies]
She didn't mean it.
You! I'm just scaring you!
So you'll learn your lesson.
And stay away from my cabin!
I'll tell my mommy and daddy.
You're a bad person!
[in English] Good!
Bring them here,
so I can smack them with your frisbee!
Go on!
[music fades]
[Audrey, in English] Girls! Uh,
dinner is ready at the dining hall.
Oh, what happened to you, my dear?
Mommy, there was a man there.
He broke our frisbee, then pinched me.
And who was that man?
Janine, you were not--
That-- That mean man.
He said
I should bring you and Daddy to his cabin,
so he could smack you with the frisbee.
Wait, I'll talk to him.
Go to the dining hall, okay.
Atoy is there.
Aunt Audrey, don't go to him!
[tense music playing]
Tatoy needs to know.
Huh?
Ibyang!
[tense music playing]
- Anybody home?
- [knock on door]
[Audrey] Hello?
- [Audrey] Hello!
It's open. Come in!
[music fades]
[mysterious music playing]
So, it's you.
I was the one who asked you earlier.
What do you want?
[Audrey] I'll be direct with you.
I didn't like what you did to my child.
What's your problem?
Ah. You're the mother of that child.
No wonder she's unruly,
because you neglected her!
[in English] Excuse me?
You're the one at fault.
You broke their toy,
and you hurt my child!
[in English] You know,
I could sue you for child abuse!
You're arrogant.
You think you're somebody.
[rousing music playing]
Do you want to know me?
Do you think I'm afraid of you?
You should be.
Because I'll be the last person
you'll ever see in your life.
[gun cocks]
[foreboding music playing]
I'm sorry for the things I said.
Um, this doesn't need to go this far.
Why did mommy suddenly act nice?
That's why there are unruly children,
- because of people like you!
- [Audrey, in English] I'm sorry.
Uh-uh, c-can we just…
forget about it?
Come here.
Come closer. Closer.
- Come closer!
- Ouch [groans]
[gasps]
[Audrey] Please, please.
[music swells]
- Come here!
- [groans]
[dramatic sting]
- [tense music playing]
- [gasping]
Is that daddy?
- What? Did you send for him?
- [sharp inhale]
Hmm?!
‪No.
- Sit, sit!
- [gasping]
‪[dramatic sting]
Let's go to that mean man.
Daddy will deal with him.
Janine, let's not go there.
That man is dangerous.
He has a gun!
A gun? You're exaggerating. He doesn't.
You're making it up.
Hmm?
I saw it earlier.
You even said he pinched you,
but he didn't.
Yes, but he almost hit me.
That's the same thing.
[dramatic sting]
[Atoy] Audrey?
Audrey!
Come in!
[door clicks open]
[ominous music playing]
Audrey?
Are you her husband?
‪[dramatic sting]
We were just talking
about what your child did earlier.
Oh, well, I'll stay with her.
Ah-- [in English] No, Atoy. I'm good.
[ominous music playing]
I'm the father of the child.
Maybe the two of us should talk instead.
We've been talking for a while.
I don't want to repeat what I said,
so you can leave now.
[dramatic sting]
Ah, okay.
[tense sting]
[Atoy] This cabin is beautiful.
So fancy.
So spacious, right?
[in English] Wow.
[tense sting]
- [Audrey screams] Atoy!
- [gunfire]
[gunfire in distance]
What's that?
That's gunfire. Let's get help.
Okay, okay.
[gunfire]
- [Audrey squeals] Atoy!
- Quick! Come with me!
[groans]
Don't follow!
- I'll kill her!
- [shrieks]
[Audrey gasping]
- Atoy!
- [gunfire]
- [squeals]
‪[Audrey gasping]
[foreboding music playing]
- [Audrey shrieks, gasping]
- Hurry up!
Let me go. If you're escaping, uh, you--
You don't need to take me.
Please, don't take me.
Looks like you have a car.
- Come on, drive for me!
- S-Sorry. I didn't bring my car keys.
You're useless!
[shrieks, gasping]
[Atoy] Sir!
Sir…
Sir, I'll go with you.
I don't trust you!
I'll help you. Sir, please.
Sir, I don't want my child
to lose her mother.
Do you have a car?
- Yes.
- Where's the key?
[ominous music playing]
Let's go. Drive for me!
- [groans]
- [squeals]
[grunting and groaning]
[groans]
[security guard] Stop!
[groaning]
[grunts]
[gasps]
Thank you, Atoy.
[sharp exhale]
[melancholic music playing]
Sir, the suspect Leon Torres
has long had an arrest warrant
for homicide in Cavite.
He went into hiding
and was only arrested now.
- Thank you.
- Thank you as well.
- We'll go ahead.
- All right.
[crickets chirping]
[Janine] Mommy!
Are you okay?
I'm-- I'm-- I'm safe, dear.
Your daddy saved me.
[Ibyang] My Tatoy is amazing.
So cool!
[pensive music playing]
Are you okay?
I know he hurt you.
[in English] I-I'm fine. I'm fine.
Do you want to go
to the hospital, see a doctor?
[in English] It's--
It's been a long day, Atoy.
Let's all rest.
Come on, dear.
[Karla] Mom, you've been quiet.
Are you upset with Sister Ame?
Not really.
Karla, maybe don't mention Delfin's name,
especially in front of your father.
Why? Is he insecure about my godfather?
- [sighs]
- [Nestor] Karla.
I saw your father drinking at the corner
with Willie, carrying liquor.
His buddy from Saudi.
I'm just telling you, okay.
Don't say I didn't try to stop him
from buying alcohol.
What time was he there?
Around two in the afternoon.
Mom, I thought he was looking for work?
Turns out he was just
drinking at the corner.
Come with me to see your father.
Leave him there. Let him sleep there.
[sighs]
Come with me.
I'll really hit Noel this time.
Let's go.
[rousing music playing]
[crickets chirping]
Here.
Put this on. It will swell.
Thank you.
So…
[crickets chirping]
What are you still doing here?
I thought you wanted to rest?
I can't sleep.
I keep thinking…
What if…
something worse happened?
Then I'd be dead.
You'd be alive. [inhales]
That's better.
At least Janine would still have
a mother. Right?
That's kind of how we are anyway.
[inhales] Think about it,
after all those years apart.
[smirks] Eight years, right?
It's like we were dead to each other.
It's different now.
What do you mean?
Nothing. Um…
I-I'll just go inside--
[gentle music playing]
What do you mean?
You don't want to lose me again?
Why can't you say it?
I don't want our child to lose her father.
[Audrey clears throat]
Is that really the only reason?
Or do you still want me?
[sentimental music playing]
[scoffs, in English] Of course not!
[sighs, then titters]
Then why did you have me tracked?
[inhales] Why did you want
the tracker to look for me,
even though your father
didn't want you to?
I know you were looking for me.
It's none of your business.
[gentle music playing]
Audrey, we're not on the island anymore.
We're not on the island to fool around.
[chuckles softly]
So, why?
Why were you searching for me?
[in English] Closure?
[in English] Second chance?
[Willie] Drink up.
Oh, ice, more ice!
- Mmm.
- Ice, ice!
- Oh.
- It makes drinking better.
- Hey, the ice!
- That's too big!
- Break it.
- Break it down.
[Cita] Noel!
- Here.
- What's this?!
I gave you money because
you said you'd look for a job.
Turns out you're just drinking!
This is called networking!
Willie will find me a job in Riyadh!
Noel, it's better if you start
a business here.
Don't take a job that will keep you
away for so long.
You don't know. Maybe…
someone's hovering around Cita. [laughs]
Cita?!
Eh-- She's old already! No one would--
You even insulted me! Go home!
[Willie] Back then,
you don't even know.
Maybe Delfin stole her away.
You know, tailors are sharp, like needles.
Sharp! [laughs]
You bastard!
- [bottle shatters]
- [groans]
That's a bad joke! That's a bad joke!
Run, you animal!
You'll be picking your guts off
the street!
- [indistinct]
- [shouts]
[Nestor] Stop it!
- Step aside, Nestor!
- No! Stop it!
Step aside!
[growls]
[tense music playing]
[gasping]
When we were on the island…
[sighs]
I came back for you.
[Atoy] You were gone.
Then I saw the necklace I gave you,
you just threw it in the trash.
[sighs]
I'll admit, I got hurt.
[gentle music playing]
Because maybe I did love you.
I didn't throw away your necklace.
I was holding it.
I waited for you because I wanted you.
[Audrey] But my father's men took me.
Then I was in a coma.
They brought me to the States and--
[sobbing]
That's why I was gone for so long.
[sobs]
Why are you only telling me this now?
[Audrey] I don't know!
And yes, that's why I had you tracked.
Because I wanted to know
if you were still alive.
If you had another family.
If-- If you still felt something for me.
[gentle music playing]
I even had a necklace made
so I wouldn't forget you!
But when I saw you…
[sobs]
I held back because…
[sniffles] It seemed
like I didn't matter to you.
Then I thought you were with Tonet.
[dramatic sting]
[Audrey] I was just holding
myself back, Atoy.
But I was hurting.
[sentimental music playing]
Audrey.
You know, even if it felt like…
like just a one-night stand between us…
I never forgot you.
That's why, when we met again,
it felt like I came alive again.
Audrey, I never loved anyone else…
since then.
Atoy,
I'm not the same Elaine
you met on the island…
to fall foolishly for you again.
Yes, I met people.
But I looked for you in all of them.
That's why none of them lasted.
[sentimental music playing]
- [sighs]
- [in English] I'm sorry.
[clears throat]
[keys jingling, then thuds]
[sentimental music playing]
[electronic blipping]
[Noel] Maybe you're forgetting!
I accepted you,
even with all your nonsense!
- That's over!
- But the evidence, it's still there!
I see it every day!
Playing basketball all the time!
And gives me a headache!
You can't sit here. Find another table.
But I want to be with Tatoy here.
And I just want to eat.
I'm still not comfortable with that Atoy.
We can't do anything, hon.
[in English] As long as they're only
doing co-parenting, we're…
we're safe for now.
[in English] You're not sure.
[Red] What if they get back together?
UP NEXT
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Oh, mister, oh, mister ♪
♪ Mr. Tailor ♪
- [electronic blipping]
- [music swells]
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias